ISciences, L.L.C. April 14, 2017

61 Main Street, Suite 200 Burlington, VT 05401

Dear Sir or Madam,

I am applying for the research scientist position at ISciences. I am a PhD student in Geophysics at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, and I anticipate graduating in August 2017. My research involves analyzing geospatial data to try to better understand processes related to plate tectonics. For example, I have used Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar (InSAR) to analyze how the ground deforms after earthquakes. Throughout my five years as a graduate student, I have developed a set a skills and techniques for geospatial data analysis. I believe that these skills will make me a valuable asset to ISciences. I have attached my resumé and I look forward to your response.

Sincerely,

Trever T. Hines

Attached: Resumé

Trever T. Hines

Education

2012-present PhD candidate Geophysics (certificate in Computational Engineering),

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

2008-2012 BS Geology, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL

Research Experience

2012-present Graduate student research assistant, University of Michigan

- Developed software to detect spatially and temporally coherent features in ground motion data
- Introduced novel techniques to infer the geophysical processes causing observable ground deformation
- 2011 **Ecological modeling intern**, Smithsonian Environmental Research Center
 - Used R and ArcGIS to create statistical models describing blue crab populations in Chesapeake Bay

Teaching Experience

2014–2016 Graduate student instructor, University of Michigan

- o Instructed labs for a graduate level course on data analysis and inverse theory
- Topics included statistical hypothesis testing, uncertainty quantification with bootstrapping, and model selection techniques such as cross validation and Bayesian information criterion.
- 2015 Michigan Math and Science Scholars instructor, University of Michigan
 - Co-taught a summer course for high school students on the mathematics of natural hazards

Proficiencies

- o Geospatial analysis using free software packages such as Basemap and Shapely
- o Bayesian statistics and supervised machine learning
- o Python, Cython, MATLAB, R, Bash, LATEX

Recent Publications

- 2017 Hines, T. T., and E. A. Hetland. Unbiased characterization of noise in geodetic data. submitted to *Journal of Geodesy*
- 2016 Hines, T. T., and E. A. Hetland. Rheologic constraints on the upper mantle from five years of postseismic deformation following the El Mayor-Cucapah earthquake. J. Geophys. Res., 121, doi: 10.1002/2016JB013114
- 2016 Hines, T. T., and E. A. Hetland. Rapid and simultaneous estimation of fault slip and heterogeneous lithospheric viscosity from post-seismic deformation. *Geophys. J. Int.*, 204, doi: 10.1093/gji/ggv477